Wilton Historical Society Wilton Historical Information Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
Wilton Historical Society Wilton Historical Information Collection
1710-2018
Wilton Historical Society (Wilton, Conn.)
WHI
25 linear feet / 7 drawers
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
The Wilton Historical Society Wilton Historical Information Collection contains newspaper clippings and magazine articles, as well as correspondence and other original documentation that goes beyond individual or family interest to relate directly to the broader history of Wilton. The collection also houses the papers, newsletters, and minutes of select local organizations. The bulk of the collection is from the late nineteenth century through the mid-twentieth century.
Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Wilton Historical Society Wilton Historical Information Collection was compiled by the Wilton Historical Society.
History
1. Wilton Historical Society Wilton Historical Information Collection
The Wilton Historical Society, founded in 1938, collected extensive materials pertaining to Wilton history. Additions have been made by Carol Russell, Wilton Historical Society Archivist and Wilton Town Historian. The majority of the material included was created by historically significant local organizations and Wilton residents, and by contributors to various periodicals and newspapers.
2. Wilton History Room
The Wilton History Room is a unique collaboration between the Wilton Historical Society (WHS) and the Wilton Library Association (WLA). Compiled beginning in 1938, the archival collections of the Wilton Historical Society had been stored in the 18th century Fitch House. In 1980, the officers and trustees of the WHS, in conversation with the director and board members of the WLA, determined that a climate controlled space, improved organization, and better public accessibility were necessary; and so in January 1984 they established a home for the collection in the Wilton Library. Organization of the collections was supported by the Cudlipp Memorial Fund and undertaken by Carol Russell. The Wilton Historical Society has retained its ownership, while the Wilton Library maintains the collections, and provides access and assistance to patrons.
The Wilton History Room is one of the most complete, organized, and well-staffed historical research facilities, for a town of our size, in Fairfield County. It is financed by the WLA, The Russell Fund, and The History Room Fund.
Today, the original archival collections of the WHS take up half of the Wilton History Room. Another quarter are library items. The collected papers of local organizations comprise the remainder: Cannon Grange, Children's Theater, Daughters of the American Revolution, Hurlbutt Street School House Association, Kiwanis Club, League of Women Voters, Rotary Club, Town Association, Weir Farm Stewardship Committee, Wilton Garden Club, Wilton Land Conservation Trust, Wilton Library, Wilton Playshop, Wilton Woman's Club, and more.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Wilton Historical Information Collection is in large part a historiographical collection: taken as a whole, it represents how Wiltonians have told their stories, and what individuals, events, businesses, places, practices, and institutions have become central to our production of local history. Contents include local histories and profiles of prominent local residents as told in newspapers and periodicals, as narrated by local historians and displayed by the Wilton Historical Society and Museum, as celebrated during Bicentennial and other commemorative events, and as followed, forsaken, or reformed in the plans that Wilton clubs, organizations, and local governing bodies have made, the reports they have produced, and the changes they have introduced.
This collection houses much of the Wilton History Room's mid- to late-twentieth century content. The frequency and number of new accessions, and the collection contents' relevance to most Wilton research questions--excepting genealogy and local houses--makes this one of our most active collections.
Arrangement
The bulk of the Wilton Historical Information Collection is arranged by topic. The Lambert Collection forms its own series within WHI, with subdivisions for business, family, house and property, and miscellaneous topics. The remainder of the collection is organized by family name, with subdivisions for artists, architects, authors, musicians, local personalities, photographers, and miscellaneous others.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
African Americans; Agriculture; American Revolution Bicentennial, 1976; Architects; Artists; Authors; Business enterprises; Cemeteries; Choral societies; Churches; City planning; Civil defense; Clubs; Historic buildings; Historic districts; Industries; Municipal government; Older people--Housing; Parks; Railroads; Roads; Schools; Societies; Sports; Trails; Trees; Wars; Weir Farm National Historic Site (Conn.); Wilton Arts Council
Related Collections
Researchers should also consult the Wilton History Room's book collection, and cross-reference their topics in the Wilton History Room's other major collections as appropriate, particularly Maps and Printed Matter. Additional complementary items may be found in Oral Histories, Microfilms, DVDs, and the Pamphlet Collection. Researchers interested in early division of Wilton lands and the Norwalk Land Records will find the Card File helpful in locating mentions of specific family names.
Separated Material
Extensive information and exhibits regarding Wilton history, including artifacts and select documentation, are in the Wilton Historical Society Museum.
- 1. People and families
  - Architects
    - Architects - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 103a)
    - Breed, Vera Poggi, 1890-1967, and Nelson Breed, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 103b)
    - Faesy, A. Robert, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 103bb)
    - Foster, Richard T., 1919-2002, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 103c)
    - Mutrux, Robert, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 103d)
    - Noyes, Eliot, 1910-1977, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 103dd)
    - Peters, Frazier Forman, 1895-1963, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 103e)
  - Artists
    See also WHI, Cartoonists, Personalities, Wilton Bulletin articles, 1881-1976
    - Andrews, Sperry, 1917-2005, undated; See also WEIR, Doris Andrews. (Cabinet 4, Folder 124a)
    - Art associations - General information, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 104)
    - Art associations - Silvermine Guild of Artists, undated; See also WHI, Art and Artists, Solon Borglum, and MCN 11-5. (Cabinet 4, Folder 105)
    - Artists - Miscellaneous, undated; Coverage begins from 1881. (Cabinet 4, Folder 108a, 108b)
    - Borglum, Solon Hannibal, 1868-1922 - General, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124ba, 124bb)
    - Borglum, Solon Hannibal, 1868-1922 - Magazine articles, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124bba)
    - Cartoonists in Wilton, undated; See also Cartoonists, Dik Browne. (Cabinet 4, Folder 139b)
    - Connecticut Artists Project, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 110)
    - Daggy, Richard Smith, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124bbaa)
    - Exhibits, undated; See also WHI, Wilton Library, exhibits. (Cabinet 4, Folder 115)
    - Federal Art Project, 1938 (Cabinet 4, Folder 124bc)
    - Galleries, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 116)
    - Haughey, Jean Ayers, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124bcb)
    - Hayes, Marvin, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124bcc)
    - Heller, Maria Jarreau, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124bd)
    - Hoban, Russell, 1925-2011 and Lillian Hoban, 1925-1998, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124c)
    - Irving, Roberta, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124d)
    - Kasper, Edward, 1922-1997, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124e)
    - Klotz, Donald L., 1925-2010 - Correspondence and writings, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124fa)
    - Klotz, Donald L., 1925-2010, and family, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 124f)
    - Kumpf, Mary, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125a)
    - Lipman, Jean, 1909-1998, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125ab)
    - Lockwood, Robert Wilton, 1861-1914 and Gutzon Borglum, 1867-1941, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125b)
    - Logan, William, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125ba)
    - Mack, Edward Beach, 1927-2016, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125bb)
    - Maydell, Baroness, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125bbb)
    - Murena, Dale, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125bc)
    - Pont, Charles Ernest, 1898-1971, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125c)
    - Prahl, Amos, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 125cb)
    - Prins, Ben Kimberly, 1902-1980, undated; See also PHO no. 170 and MCN 11-3. (Cabinet 4, Folder 125d)
    - Proctor, Alexander Phimister, 1860-1950, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 126a)
    - Proctor, Gifford MacGregor, 1912-2006, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 126aa)
    - Roberts, Priscilla, 1916-2001, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 126b)
    - Rubino, Peter, 1947-, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 126c)
    - S. Van Haelewyn, Hendrick, 1898-1992, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 129b)
    - Schmitt, Carl, 1889-1989, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 127a)
    - Smith, Elmer Boyd, 1860-1943, undated; See also WHI, Printed Matter no. 152. (Cabinet 4, Folder 128a)
    - Smith, Thomas Herbert, 1875-1945, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 127b)
    - Squires, Mac, 1908-1981, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 128b)
    - Stock, Ernest, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 128b)
    - Stuart, Kenneth J., d. 1993, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 128c)
    - Thomson, Henry Grinnell, 1850-1937, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 129a)
    - Weir, Julian Alden, 1852-1919, undated; See also WHI, Personalities. (Cabinet 4, Folder 129c)
    - Wilton Arts Council - “Sculpture: Inside and Outside”, 1993 (Cabinet 4, Folder 106i)
    - Wilton Arts Council - Annual Meetings, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 106a)
    - Wilton Arts Council - Board of Directors, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 106b)
    - Wilton Arts Council - Calendar and newsletters, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 106c)
    - Wilton Arts Council - Festivals, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 106d)
    - Wilton Arts Council - Members, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 106e)
    - Wilton Arts Council - Miscellaneous programs and events, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 106h)
    - Wilton Arts Council - Photos, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 106f)
    - Wilton Arts Council - Publicity, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 106g)
    - Young, Mahonri M., 1877-1957, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 129d)
  - Authors
    - Authors - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 130a)
    - Baker, Adelaide N., undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 130ab)
    - Ballston, New York, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 132)
    - D'Aulaire, Ingri, 1904-1980 and Edgar Parin d’Aulaire, 1898-1986, undated; See also Art and Artists in Library Archives (Art Shows). (Cabinet 4, Folder 130b)
    - Glattstein, Judy, 1942-, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 131a)
    - Harrington, Gerry and Peter Tyrus Harrington, 1951-, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 131b)
    - Jessup, Eunice Clark, 1911-1987 and John Jessup, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 131c)
    - Kopit, Arthur, 1937- and Leslie Garis, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 131d)
    - Littledale, Freya, 1929-, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 131e)
    - Margolis, Richard J. and Diane Rothbard Margolis, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 131f)
    - Ogden, F. Clerc - "Oldtimer" articles, undated; See also Books 811.54 Ogden and 920.097469 Ogden. (Cabinet 4, Folder 424b)
  - Miscellaneous
    - African Americans, undated; See also in WHI “Black Jack” Tonquin and Cesar Comstock, and in GEN Manning. (Cabinet 4, Folder 415)
    - Appleby, Dr. Robert, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 339a)
    - Comstock, Cesar, 1709-1773, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 484)
    - Gold, Dr. Harold, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 339aa)
    - Hall of Volunteers, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 450)
    - Native Americans / American Indians, 1930-1972; File includes map of local trails and villages. (Cabinet 4, Folder 320)
    - Obituaries of Wilton residents, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 423)
    - Verilli, Rosemarie - Testimonials in her honor, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 505)
    - Vital Statistics, undated; See also WHI, Census, and Book 285.87469 Records. (Cabinet 4, Folder 554)
    - Wilton House, 2000s; This file contains information on the historical house located in Richmond, Virginia. (Cabinet 5, Folder 755b)
    - Wilton women, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 756)
  - Musicians
    - Brings / Chinn, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413aa)
    - Brubeck family, undated; See also PHO. (Cabinet 4, Folder 410cb)
    - Brubeck, David and family, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413ab)
    - Crofut, William, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413aba)
    - Hadley, Jerry, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413abb)
    - Jones, Betty, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413ac)
    - Lauer, Liz, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413b)
    - Lavalle, Paul, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413bb)
    - Leadbelly, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413c, 413ca)
    - Musicians - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413a)
    - Parisot, Aldo, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413cb)
    - Rocherolle, Eugenie, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 413d)
  - Personalities
    - Alcosser, Lois - Index to Wilton Bulletin articles on personalities, undated; Indexed articles are in box Bulletin Articles by Lois Alcosser, on Black Bookshelf 20. (Cabinet 4, Folder 430)
    - Bassett, Walter, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 430b)
    - Bradley, Leonard, 1900-1970, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 431a)
    - Breed, Vera Poggi, 1890-1967, and Nelson Breed, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 431b)
    - Burt, Basil, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 431c)
    - Canary, David, 1938-2015, and Maureen Canary, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 431ca)
    - Carpenter, Anna, undated; See also WHI, Herbarium. (Cabinet 4, Folder 431d)
    - Dana, Charles, 1881-1966, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 432a)
    - Davenport, Sarah, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 432b)
    - Dibner, Dr. Bern, 1897-1988, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 432bb)
    - Donahue, Thomas, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 432bbb)
    - Duffy, Mary, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 432c)
    - Gill, Margaret “Peggy”, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 432d)
    - Goslee, Harvey, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433a)
    - Gould, Marilyn, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433aa)
    - Gregory, Edith, 1898-1985, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433b)
    - Grodin, Charles, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433bb)
    - Gross, Herbert, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433bba)
    - Higby, Hal and Judy, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433bbaa)
    - Hopkins, Joseph, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433bbb)
    - Hottelet, Richard C., 1917-2014, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433bc)
    - Hubbard, G. Evans, 1891-1950, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 433c)
    - Jones, Eugene "Doug", undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 434a)
    - Leatherman, 1817-1889, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 434b)
    - Lilly, Kristine, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 434ba)
    - Lipman, Jean, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 434c)
    - Lynch, Kenneth, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 435a)
    - Mattson, Rolan, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 435b)
    - Merwin, Tim, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 435bb)
    - Miller, Tilford, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 435bbb)
    - Ogden, F. Clerc, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 435c)
    - Peanut Lady, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 435ca)
    - Personalities - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 430a)
    - Piersall, Ralph, undated; See also OH. (Cabinet 4, Folder 435d)
    - Post, Angeline, 1878-1974, undated; See also HSSR. (Cabinet 4, Folder 436a)
    - Russell, Robert H. “Bob” and Carol Russell, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 436b)
    - Schenck, Grace, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 437a)
    - Smith, Walter R. T., undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 437a)
    - Spencer, William - “A Connecticut Yankee”, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 437b)
    - Stuart, Moses, 1780-1852, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 439)
    - Tonquin, "Black" Jack, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 430c)
    - Turner, J. Edward, 1822-1889, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 440)
    - Van Hoosear, David Hermon, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 441)
    - Verilli, Rosemarie, 1981; See also OH. (Cabinet 4, Folder 442)
    - Von Kleydorff, Ludwig, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 444)
    - Weir, Julian Alden, 1852-1919, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 445a)
    - Whitney, Joseph, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 445b)
    - Whittlesley, Julian, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 445c)
    - Winton, Andrew B., 1864-1946, undated; See also Books. (Cabinet 4, Folder 446)
    - Winton, Kate, 1882-1974, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 447)
  - Photographers
    - Jackson, Edward Norman, 1885-1967, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 450a)
    - Steichen, Edward J., 1879–1973, and Kate Steichen, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 438)
- 2. Lambert collection
  - Businesses
    - Lambert Brothers Company - Correspondence, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-180)
    - Lambert Brothers Company - G. Evans Hubbard notes, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-190)
    - Lambert Tavern, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-530)
  - Family
    - Chronology, circa 1938; Chronology begins in 1655 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-120)
    - Family portraits, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-110)
    - Family tree, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-150)
    - Hubbard, G. Evans - Notes, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-140)
    - Lambert family history, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-160)
    - Lambert genealogy - Correspondence, 1939-1977 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-130)
    - Lambert, David, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-200)
    - Lambert, David - Purchase of a slave, 1757 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-205)
    - Lambert, David Jr., undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-210)
    - Lambert, David Rogers, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-220)
    - Lambert, David Samuel Rogers, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-230)
    - Lambert, David Samuel Rogers - Murder, 1897; See also MC 7-4 for copies of newspaper articles collection. (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-235)
    - Lambert, Jesse, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-250)
    - Lambert, John James, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-260)
    - Lambert, Julia, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-270)
    - Lambert, Mrs. Samuel F. (Esther), undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-240)
    - Lambert, Samuel Fitch, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-280)
    - Lambert, Susannah (Rogers), undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-290)
    - Lambert, Susannah (Rogers) and David II - Children, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-195)
    - Lambert, Tallmadge A., undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-300)
    - Russell, Robert H. - Lambert family history talk, 2016; Robert H. Russell gave his talk on June 23, 2016. (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-305)
    - Slide talk, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-320)
    - St. Matthew's Episcopal Church - Records, 1819-1828 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-310)
  - House and property
    - Architecture, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-340)
    - Bicentennial Medal, 1976 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-350)
    - Chronology, 1722-1924, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-360)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-380)
    - Deeds, 1717-1850 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-100)
    - Dining room furniture - Exhibit, 1969 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-370)
    - Fund raising, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-372)
    - Gregg, Kenneth P., undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-420)
    - Inventory of real estate, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-170)
    - Kellogg, Royal and Ruth, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-430)
    - Lambert house - History, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-400)
    - Minor, Gladys and Howard - Renters, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-440)
    - Museum - Wilton Historical Society ownership, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-410)
    - Photographs, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-390, LAM-450)
    - Powell, B. W. - Archeological excavation, 1972-1973 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-335)
    - Purchase, 1962 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-452)
    - Wills, undated (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-330)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Crookshank-Lambert - Correspondence, 1801-1961; See also typed transcriptions of Lambert-Crookshank correspondence in a box on Black Shelf 20. (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-490)
    - Greene, Valerie - Research, 1963-1964 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-460)
    - Inquiry of family - Correspondence, 1965-1971 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-500)
    - Lambert - Miscellaneous, 1964-1971 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-470)
    - Tunnel, 1961 (Cabinet 18, Folder LAM-480)
- 3. Miscellaneous (by topic)
  - Accidents, crimes, and disasters
    - Anderson, Susan - Murder, 1898 (Cabinet 4, Folder 229c)
    - Blizzard of 1888, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 231)
    - Crimes and misdemeanors - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 229d)
    - Crimes in 1754 (Cabinet 4, Folder 229e)
    - Eruption of Mount Tambora / Year Without a Summer, 1816 (Cabinet 4, Folder 233c)
    - Flood - Danbury Pictorial Review, undated; Coverage includes a photograph of the flood. (Cabinet 4, Folder 232b)
    - Flood of 1955, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 232a)
    - Floods - Wilton Bulletin articles, undated; See also OH folder 215, tapes 32a and 32b. (Cabinet 4, Folder 232d)
    - Floods in Norwalk, Stamford, Danbury, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 232c)
    - Gale of 1821, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 233a)
    - Hurricane of 1938, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 233ab)
    - Ice storm 1973, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 233b)
    - Maudlin - Murder, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 229a)
    - Plane crash, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 233bb)
    - Railroad, airplane, and hayride accidents, 1853-1913 (Cabinet 4, Folder 541)
    - Stuart, William - Crimes and misdemeanors, 1854 (Cabinet 4, Folder 229b)
  - Agriculture and livestock
    - Barnes Cattle Farm, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 275b)
    - Cannon Grange, undated; See also Books 630.6 Cannon. (Cabinet 4, Folder 139a)
    - Caterpillar Defoliation Report, 1971 (Cabinet 4, Folder 139c)
    - Chance Hill Farm (Firestone), undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 275c)
    - Cole Fruit Farm, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 276a)
    - Crop Walk - Dance, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 229h)
    - Crop Walk - Newspaper articles, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 229f)
    - Crop Walk - Press releases, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 229g)
    - Deer Management, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 229i)
    - Farm Journal (Danbury), 1790-1802 (Cabinet 4, Folder 401)
    - Farming in New England, 1861 (Cabinet 4, Folder 101aa)
    - Gilbert family farm, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 101b)
    - Gilbert Farm, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 276b)
    - Gunning family farm, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 102a)
    - Hurlbutt Farm, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 276c)
    - Jackson Farm, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 277)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 101a)
    - Offinger Farm, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 278)
    - Passport to Weir Farm, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 679d)
    - Stone walls, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 730a)
    - Stone walls, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 492)
    - Tobacco Farming, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 279)
    - Veterinarians, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 553)
    - Weir family, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 679g)
    - Weir Farm - Maps, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 679e)
    - Weir Farm - Miscellaneous, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 679a, 679b)
    - Weir Farm Art Center, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 679f)
    - Weir Farm Trust, undated (Cabinet 5, Folder 679c)
    - Wilton Farm Bureau, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 102b)
  - Business and industry
    See also WHI, Merchants, Stores or Industries; and Printed Matter, Wilton Business Directory.
    - Angelique Perfume Factory, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 137aa)
    - Banking, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 133a)
    - Bee keeping, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 133b)
    - Betts & Raymond Store - Accounts, 1800-1827 (Cabinet 4, Folder 344)
    - Betts Store, 1780-1878; See also BS. (Cabinet 4, Folder 342)
    - Blacksmiths and silversmiths, undated; See also WHI, Personalities, Kenneth Lynch. (Cabinet 4, Folder 322a)
    - Bradley Axe Works, undated (Cabinet 4, Folder 137b)